<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>{ titanium cranium }</title>
		<description>Blog and website of Brendan J. O&apos;Brien, creating worlds for mind and machine alike.</description>
		<link>https://titanium-cranium.github.io</link>
		<atom:link href="https://titanium-cranium.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>From Certificate to Environment Variable</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;G’day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>https://titanium-cranium.github.io/ruby%20code/2017/08/30/Certificate.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://titanium-cranium.github.io/ruby%20code/2017/08/30/Certificate.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How YAML ruined my day...</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi All:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>https://titanium-cranium.github.io/job%20hunt%20diary/2017/08/25/Days7-9.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://titanium-cranium.github.io/job%20hunt%20diary/2017/08/25/Days7-9.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Back in the saddle again...</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Wow…after 1.5 years employed doing object-oriented programming in Java, I found myself struggling a bit the past couple days with code challenges. For those of you that aren’t aware, interviews for programmers generally involve a “code test” of some sort. These tests are designed to check your skill level at creating an algorithm to solve some form of complex problem.  You can think of them like a ‘riddle’ in a way. Skill is assessed in a number of ways, accuracy of the solution being just one aspect. Simple and succinct code being another.  The code challenges, however, are generally short self-contained problems that may test your mathematical prowess but have next to nothing to do with actual web development. Despite this fact, code challenges are routinely used and I’d better be ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, I logged in on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hackerrank.com&quot;&gt;HackerRank&lt;/a&gt;, one of the many sites which purport to test your skill level. Unfortunately, while I’d been spending all my work time slinging objects in and out of databases, creating, updating, listing, transforming and deleting them as well, I haven’t had much need to practice using the many and varied methods built into Ruby and Java. I’ve been mainly creating my own methods to deal with my employer’s unique datasets. As a result, I am out of practice. Perhaps it would have been a good idea to start each day with a code challenge just to stay on top of it.  I think that might not be a bad idea from here on out. In the meantime, it’ll be a bit of a slog as I get back up to speed. Fortunately, my Google-Fu is pretty good so I can find an answer on the net without much delay. What I’m unhappy about, however, is that I’ve let it eclipse what I need to do on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robotcombatevents.com&quot;&gt;passion project&lt;/a&gt;. Starting tomorrow, I’ll have to enforce a hard limit on how much time I spend doing algorithms and get the real work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ciao for now!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>https://titanium-cranium.github.io/job%20hunt%20diary/2017/08/21/Day5-6.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://titanium-cranium.github.io/job%20hunt%20diary/2017/08/21/Day5-6.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Day 4</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Well, unfortunately, no progress was made on the job hunt today.  This is both good and bad.  Got to spend a bit of time with the family, which was good.  But also spent a fair bit of time with car mechanics, which was bad.  Will have to get stuck in tomorrow morning until I get to enjoy being Dad and watch as my son tries on his best impression of Alexi Lalas on the soccer pitch, the legendary American defender.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>https://titanium-cranium.github.io/job%20hunt%20diary/2017/08/19/Day4.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://titanium-cranium.github.io/job%20hunt%20diary/2017/08/19/Day4.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Plan</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve been busy making a to-do list for the job hunt.  This is what I have so far.  I’m open to all ideas, suggestions, constructive comments and dopeslaps you would like to provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;plan-of-attack-in-no-particular-order&quot;&gt;Plan of attack (in no particular order)&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>https://titanium-cranium.github.io/job%20hunt%20diary/2017/08/18/the-plan.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://titanium-cranium.github.io/job%20hunt%20diary/2017/08/18/the-plan.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Day 3</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Spent a fair bit of time working on updating my professional social media sites.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/bjobrienphd/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/users/story/5748167&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt; are now up to date and application ready. Both of them provide a resume style PDF download which I’m considering using when requested though I’m not certain that’s such a great idea.  Anyone have thoughts on this issue?  I’ve also contacted a recruiter whose helping me shape my plans and provided some great resources to help prepare me for the impending interviews (Thanks &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lookahead.com.au/&quot;&gt;Toby!&lt;/a&gt;).  I’ve never actually had to do a live code test so I’m a bit worried as to how I’ll fare.  Under pressure like that I’m worried I might lock up.  Given a long history of lecturing in front of hundreds of University students, I’m used to stress like that.  But where I am an expert neuroscientist, I am still early in my coding career.  This is where I’m hoping &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hackerrank.com/&quot;&gt;HackerRank&lt;/a&gt; might come in handy. I will also make sure to refresh my memory of the algorithmic challenges I did when enrolled in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thefirehoseproject.com&quot;&gt;The Firehose Project&lt;/a&gt; coder bootcamp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, I’ll get stuck into getting my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robotcombatevents.com&quot;&gt;app&lt;/a&gt; up to speed and try to finish off integrating Paypal so the event organizers can start taking registration fees directly through the site. It’s kinda working now, but needs additional encryption and security before I’ll be ready to let it go live. That’s &lt;b&gt;real&lt;/b&gt; money changing hands so I want it flawless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok everyone, that’s all for now.  Until tomorrow!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>https://titanium-cranium.github.io/job%20hunt%20diary/2017/08/18/Day3.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://titanium-cranium.github.io/job%20hunt%20diary/2017/08/18/Day3.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Redundant?</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I walked into work as per normal, strong flat-white in hand, only to discover I’d been made ‘redundant.’  This came as quite a shock. I’d only been with the company just over a year and my annual review gave me no indication that my performance was unsatisfactory.  Quite the opposite.  As it turns out, my boss assured me it had nothing to do with my performance, just that the management team had decided my role was no longer necessary for the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;well-crap-that-sucks&quot;&gt;Well, crap… that sucks.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>https://titanium-cranium.github.io/job%20hunt%20diary/2017/08/17/redundant.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://titanium-cranium.github.io/job%20hunt%20diary/2017/08/17/redundant.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>I speak well Ruby</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;In my former career as a scientist, I had the life changing opportunity to live and work overseas. The fresh-faced boy that I was from Podunk, America moved to the slick city of Frankfurt am Main in Germany. While I was assured by my future colleagues long before I moved, that everyone in Germany speaks English, they lied. Life outside the laboratory for me meant learning German or learning charades. When you’re in the grocery store and you know you need batteries but you can’t find them and you have no idea what the German word for ‘battery’ is, it’s either a humorous and humbling game of charades, or your wireless keyboard stays dead (True story. The most silly part though is that I was so committed to not using English that it only prolonged the whole affair because German for battery is in fact, ‘Batterie’).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>https://titanium-cranium.github.io/coding/2015/11/24/learning-ruby.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://titanium-cranium.github.io/coding/2015/11/24/learning-ruby.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
